### **GIRISH KUMAR KANNAN**

girishkumar.kannan@gmail.com (407) 633-8501

https://www.linkedin.com/in/girish-kumar-kannan https://www.github.com/GirishKumarK

1050 7th Street #2, Miami Beach, Florida, 33139.

### **SUMMARY**

An M.S.Cp.E graduate with 3 years of professional computer engineering experience and a wide range of technical skills. Focused in Robotics, Computer Vision and Machine Learning. Excels at Programming, Data Engineering and Database Systems. Versatile and hardworking, passionate towards contributing to a team to accelerate outcomes and goals. Takes personal responsibility and accountable to assigned tasks. Motivated towards developing quality technologies, systems and processes. Quick learner and problem solver.

#### **EDUCATION**

University of Central Florida, Orlando, Florida, USA.

August 2016 - May 2018

# **Master of Science in Computer Engineering**

CGPA: 3.5 / 4.0

Related Coursework: Advanced A.I., Machine Learning, Intelligent Systems, Computer Vision, Digital Signal Processing. Related Projects:

- Prediction & Signal Smoothening w/ Kalman Filter: Engineered robot & algorithm to obtain Magnetic Heading from Digital IMU using Arduino with C/C++ program.
- Occupancy Grid-based 2D-SLAM Robot: Deployed A-Star Search and Reinforcement Learning techniques to navigate a robot that can Simultaneously Localize and Map a quasi-stochastic region using Matlab, C/C++ and Python.
- Multi-Detection Computer Vision: Developed a set of Computer Vision algorithms to make a webcam detect hand gestures as mouse commands and perform Optical Character Recognition as well, on a real-time basis.
- Mini-Projects in Computer Vision: Implemented and presented common Computer Vision Algorithms and Convolutional Neural Network based Image and Action Sequence Classification - all from scratch using Scikit-Learn and Tensorflow in Python.
- Programmed and compared Machine Learning algorithms to datasets to understand the efficiency of every algorithm using R and Python (numpy, scipy, pandas, seaborn and scikit-learn).
- Designed and demonstrated various Signal Filters and Processing techniques to analyze the efficiency of each design using Matlab.

SRM University, Chennai, Tamil Nadu, India.

August 2011 - May 2015

## **Bachelor of Technology in Mechatronics**

CGPA: 8.9 / 10.0

### Related Projects:

- Autonomous Robot Swarm for Goal Searching: Designed an Arduino-based three-agent swarm that uses Alpha-Beta Coordination Algorithm using C/C++ for Goal Searching and Convergence for applications like search and rescue and resource foraging. Related Publication: "On the Estimation of Optimal Robot Heading using Savitzky-Golay and Kalman Filters", International Journal of Robotics and Automation, 2015.
- Gesture Controlled Mouse: Designed an Arduino-based Wireless Gesture-controlled Mouse using Inertial Sensor to aid people with limb-disabilities. Built and programmed an interface that translated hand gestures to cursor actions on a computer using C/C++.

### TECHNICAL SKILLS

Operating Systems: Windows (10+years), Linux (3+ years – Ubuntu, Debian, Raspbian)

Programming Languages: Python (NumPy, SciPy, Pandas, MatPlotLib, Seaborn), Matlab, C, C++, SQL, [ Java, C#, HTML, R ]

Applications: OpenCV, TensorFlow, Tkinter, PyQt, Git, Ms Office, Libre Office

### WORK EXPERIENCE

# Roboticist / Robotics Engineer, Quartile 3 Robotics, Miami Beach, Florida, USA.

Nov 2018 – Present

Developed a program with GUI that will help take Restaurant orders using Speech Synthesis and Facial Recognition in Python.

- Developed GUI to actuate a Humanoid Robot by a Remote User, controlled through intranet & internet using Python and Tkinter.
- Developed Communication Protocol for Ultra Long Range Transceiver pair. Produced error-free and loss-less transfer.
- Developed API in Python to interface a GPS RTK device. Decoded, interpreted and reformatted incoming binary data.
- Developed APIs for all the above projects to handle automated data interaction between local and cloud SQL database servers.

### Computer Engineer Intern, Parsound LLC, Orlando, Florida, USA.

Aug 2018 – Jan 2019

- Lead engineering teams of up to 10 people, conducted interviews and made important decisions.
- Designed and developed advanced DSP algorithms, signal communication strategy and device communication topologies.
- Developed a program in Python to handle automatic data exchange between a software and a data file. Collected, reorganized, transformed and exported the data file to be imported directly into the software. Handled data errors and corrections.
- Collaborated across disciplines to make user-friendly amplifier control systems, effectively automating smart soundscapes.

# DSP Engineer (Volunteer-Associate), Parseval LLC, Orlando, Florida, USA.

May 2017 – April 2018

- Developed a project that saves trapped lives in a vehicle endangered by unsafe temperatures. Fabricated and designed circuit boards, assembled, analyzed and tested the efficacy of the design. Programmed using C/C++ and Python.
- Designed and programmed automated microphone stand to perceive soundscape of a room using Matlab. Procured components, created CAD models and 3D printed, programmed device control, tested product design and evaluated working efficiency.